<resources>

    <string name="app_name">TSSFPrayers</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">Community Obedience Prayer</string>
    <string name="TSSFAboutTitle">About</string>
    <string name="TSSFAboutDialog">About this app.</string>
    <string name="TSSFAbout">This application is built to assist brothers and sisters of the Third Order of the Society of St. Francis (TSSF) with their Community Obedience Prayer. It is used on its own or in conjunction with morning or evening prayer.\nIf you see anything that needs fixing in the application or you are experiencing problems with the application contact:\nGordon Hooker gorhook@gmail.com\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFEmail">gorhook@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="TSSFDeveloper">Gordon Hooker</string>
    <string name="TSSFDailyObedienceExplain">For use alone or in conjunction with morning prayer.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFOpeningPrayer">Here and in all your churches throughout the world, we adore you, O Christ, and we bless you, because by your holy cross you have redeemed the world. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFGloriaPatra">In the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCommunityPrayer">\nGod, we give you thanks for the Third Order of the Society of St. Francis. Grant, we pray, that being knit together in community and prayer, we your servants may glorify your holy name after the example of Saint Francis, and win others to your love; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFBlessing1">Blessing A.\nMay our blessed Lady pray for us.\nMay Saint Francis pray for us.\nMay Saint Clare pray for us.\nMay all the saints of the Third Order pray for us.\nMay the holy angels watch over us and befriend us.\nMay our Lord Jesus give us his blessing and his peace. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFBlessing2">Blessing B.\nThe grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, the love of God, and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us all evermore. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCopyRight">Text and Prayers reproduced with the permission of the TSSF Australian Province with Papua New Guinea and South-East Asia.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFAboutDocument">In all provinces of the Third Order this offering of prayer should be made daily, either on its own or in the context of Morning or Evening Prayer</string>
    <string name="TSSFAboutExplain">About Daily Obedience Prayer.</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrivateTitle">Private Prayer</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrivateExplain">Private Prayer Points.</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrivateAbout">1 to 7 for weekday, other value to show daily.</string>
    <string name="TSSFNoIntercessionList">Intercession prayers go here.</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrivateIntercession">Private Intercession List.</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrincipleRubric">Principle for day</string>
    <string name="TSSFIntercessionRubric">Daily intercession list for day</string>
    <string name="TSSFBlessingRubric1">The offering of prayer may continue with either Morning or Evening Prayer or conclude with either of the following:\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFBlessingRubric2">or\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollectRubric">Collect for the day may be said here.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect1">God, your love led Francis and Clare to establish our three orders: draw us into your love that we may grow in love towards all those we know, for the sake of your Son, Jesus Christ, who gives himself in love to all. Amen.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect2">God, you are always pleased to show yourself to those who are childlike and humble in spirit: help us to follow the example of our blessed father Francis, to look upon the wisdom of this world as foolishness, and to set our minds only on Christ Jesus and him crucified; to whom with you and the Holy Spirit be all glory for ever. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect3">God, you resist the proud and give grace to the humble: help us not to think proudly, but to serve you with the humility that pleases you, so we may walk in the steps of your servant Francis and receive the gift of your grace; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect4">God, you have made your church rich through the poverty of blessed Francis: help us, like him, not to trust in earthly things, but to seek your heavenly gifts; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect5">God, by the life of blessed Francis you moved your people to a love of simple things: may we, after his example hold lightly to the things of this world and store up for ourselves treasure in heaven; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect6">Lord Jesus, in your servant Francis you displayed the wonderful power of the cross: help us always to follow you in the way of the cross, and give us strength to resist all temptation, and to you, Lord, with the Father and the Holy Spirit be all glory for ever. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFCollect7">Lord, without you our labour is wasted, but with you all who are weak can find strength: pour your Spirit on the Society of Saint Francis; give your labourers a pure intention, patient faith, sufficient success on earth, and the joy of serving you in heaven; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple1">The Object\nJesus said, "Very truly, I tell you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains just a single grain; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Those who love their life lose it, and those who hate their life in this world will keep it for eternal life. Whoever serves me must follow me, and where I am, there will my servant be also. Whoever serves me, the Father will honor." (John 12:24 to 26)\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple2">The Object, cont\'d\nIn the example of his own sacrifice, Jesus reveals the secret of bearing fruit. In surrendering himself to death, he becomes the source of new life. Lifted from the earth on the cross, he draws all people to himself. Clinging to life causes life to decay; the life that is freely given is eternal.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple3">The Object, cont\'d\nJesus calls those who would serve him to follow his example and choose for themselves the same path of renunciation and sacrifice. To those who hear and obey he promises union with God. The object of the Society of Saint Francis is to build a community of those who accept Christ as their Lord and Master and are dedicated to him in body and spirit. They surrender their lives to him and to the service of his people. The Third Order of the Society consists of those who, while following the ordinary professions of life, feel called to dedicate their lives under a definite discipline and vows. They may be female or male, married or single, ordained or lay.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple4">The Object, cont\'d\nWhen Saint Francis encouraged the formation of the Third Order he recognized that many are called to serve God in the spirit of Poverty, Chastity, and Obedience in everyday life (rather than in a literal acceptance of these principles as in the vows of the Brothers and Sisters of the First and Second Orders). The Rule of the Third Order is intended to enable the duties and conditions of daily living to be carried out in this spirit.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple5">The First Aim of the Order\nTo make our Lord known and loved everywhere. - The Order is founded on the conviction that Jesus Christ is the perfect revelation of God; that true life has been made available to us through his Incarnation and Ministry, by his Cross and Resurrection, and by the sending of his Holy Spirit. The Order believes that it is the commission of the church to make the gospel known to all, and therefore accepts the duty of bringing others to know Christ, and of praying and working for the coming of the Kingdom of God.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple6">The First Aim, cont\'d\nThe primary aim for us as tertiaries is therefore to make Christ known. This shapes our lives and attitudes to reflect the obedience of those whom our Lord chose to be with him and sent out as his witnesses. Like them, by word and example, we bear witness to Christ in our own immediate environment and pray and work for the fulfillment of his command to make disciples of all nations.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple7">The Second Aim - To spread the spirit of love and harmony - The Order sets out, in the name of Christ, to break down barriers between people and to seek equality for all. We accept as our second aim the spreading of a spirit of love and harmony among all people. We are pledged to fight against the ignorance, pride, and prejudice that breed injustice or partiality of any kind.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple8">The Second Aim, cont\'d\nMembers of the Third Order fight against all such injustice in the name of Christ, in whom there can be neither Jew nor Greek, slave nor free, male nor female; for in him all are one. Our chief object is to reflect that openness to all which was characteristic of Jesus. This can only be achieved in a spirit of chastity, which sees others as belonging to God and not as a means of self-fulfillment.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple9">The Second Aim, cont\'d\nAs Tertiaries, we are prepared not only to speak out for social justice and international peace, but to put these principles into practice in our own lives, cheerfully facing any scorn or persecution to which this may lead.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple10">The Third Aim - To live simply\nThe first Christians surrendered completely to our Lord and recklessly gave all that they had, offering the world a new vision of a society in which a fresh attitude was taken towards material possessions. This vision was renewed by Saint Francis when he chose Lady Poverty as his bride, desiring that all barriers set up by privilege based on wealth should be overcome by love. This is the inspiration for the third aim of the Society, to live simply.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple11">The Third Aim, cont\'d\nAlthough we possess property and earn money to support ourselves and our families, we show ourselves to be true followers of Christ and of Saint Francis by our readiness to live simply and to share with others. We recognize that some of our members may be called to a literal following of Saint Francis in a life of extreme simplicity. All of us, however, accept that we avoid luxury and waste, and regard our possessions as being held in trust for God.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple12">The Third Aim, cont\'d\nPersonal spending is limited to what is necessary for our health and well-being and that of our dependents. We aim to stay free from all attachment to wealth, keeping ourselves constantly aware of the poverty in the world and its claim on us. We are concerned more for the generosity that gives all, rather than the value of poverty in itself. In this way we reflect in spirit the acceptance of Jesus\' challenge to sell all, give to the poor, and follow him.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple13">The Three Ways of Service\nTertiaries desire to be conformed to the image of Jesus Christ, whom we serve in the three ways of Prayer, Study, and Work. In the life of the Order as a whole these three ways must each find full and balanced expression, but it is not to be expected that all members devote themselves equally to each of them. Each individual\'s service varies according to his/her abilities and circumstances, yet the member\'s personal rule of life includes each of the three ways.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple14">The First Way of Service - Prayer\nTertiaries seek to live in an atmosphere of praise and prayer. We aim to be constantly aware of God\'s presence, so that we may indeed pray without ceasing. Our ever deepening devotion to the indwelling Christ is a source of strength and joy. It is Christ\'s love that inspires us to service, and strengthens us for sacrifice.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple15">The First Way of Service, cont\'d\nThe heart of our prayer is the Eucharist, in which we share with other Christians the renewal of our union with our Lord and Savior in his sacrifice, remembering his death and receiving his spiritual food.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple16">The First Way of Service, cont\'d\nTertiaries recognize the power of intercessory prayer for furthering the purposes of God\'s kingdom, and therefore seek a deepening communion with God in personal devotion, and constantly intercede for the needs of his church and his world. Those of us who have much time at our disposal give prayer a large part in our daily lives. Those of us with less time must not fail to see the importance of prayer and to guard the time we have allotted to it from interruption. Lastly, we are encouraged to avail ourselves of the sacrament of Reconciliation, through which the burden of past sin and failure is lifted and peace and hope restored.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple17">The Second Way of Service - Study\n"And this is eternal life: that they may know you the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent." (John 17:3) True knowledge is knowledge of God. Tertiaries therefore give priority to devotional study of scripture as one of the chief means of attaining that knowledge of God which leads to eternal life.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple18">The Second Way of Service, cont\'d\nAs well as the devotional study of Scripture, we all recognize our Christian responsibility to pursue other branches of study, both sacred and secular. In particular, some of us accept the duty of contributing, through research and writing, to a better understanding of the church\'s mission in the world: the application of Christian principles to the use and distribution of wealth; questions concerning justice and peace; and of all other questions concerning the life of faith.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple19">The Third Way of Service - Work\nJesus took on himself the form of a servant. He came not to be served, but to serve. He went about doing good: healing the sick, preaching good news to the poor, and binding up the broken hearted.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple20">The Third Way of Service, cont\'d\nTertiaries endeavor to serve others in active work. We try to find expression for each of the three aims of the Order in our lives, and whenever possible actively help others who are engaged in similar work. The chief form of service which we have to offer is to reflect the love of Christ, who, in his beauty and power, is the inspiration and joy of our lives.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple21">The Three Notes of the Order\nHumility, love, and joy are the three notes which mark the lives of Tertiaries. When these characteristics are evident throughout the Order, its work will be fruitful. Without them, all that it attempts will be in vain.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple22">The First Note - Humility\nWe always keep before us the example of Christ, who emptied himself, taking the form of a servant, and who, on the last night of his life, humbly washed his disciples\' feet. We likewise seek to serve one another with humility.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple23">The First Note, cont\'d\nHumility confesses that we have nothing that we have not received and admits the fact of our insufficiency and our dependence upon God. It is the basis of all Christian virtues. Saint Bernard of Clairvaux said, "No spiritual house can stand for a moment except on the foundation of humility." It is the first condition of a joyful life within any community.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple24">The First Note, cont\'d\nThe faults that we see in others are the subject of prayer rather than of criticism. We take care to cast out the beam from our own eye before offering to remove the speck from another\'s. We are ready to accept the lowest place when asked, and to volunteer to take it. Nevertheless, when asked to undertake work of which we feel unworthy or incapable, we do not shrink from it on the grounds of humility, but confidently attempt it through the power that is made perfect in weakness.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple25">The Second Note - Love\nJesus said, "I give you a new commandment: love one another. Just as I have loved you, you also should love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another." (John 13:34 to 35) Love is the distinguishing feature of all true disciples of Christ who wish to dedicate themselves to him as his servants.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple26">The Second Note, cont\'d\nTherefore, we seek to love all those to whom we are bound by ties of family or friendship. Our love for them increases as our love for Christ grows deeper. We have a special love and affection for members of the Third Order, praying for each other individually and seeking to grow in that love. We are on our guard against anything which might injure this love, and we seek reconciliation with those from whom we are estranged. We seek the same love for those with whom we have little natural affinity, for this kind of love is not a welling up of emotion, but is a bond founded in our common union with Christ.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple27">The Second Note, cont\'d\nThe Third Order is a Christian community whose members, although varied in race, education, and character, are bound into a living whole through the love we share in Christ. This unity of all who believe in him will become, as our Lord intended, a witness to the world of his divine mission. In our relationship with those outside the Order, we show the same Christ-like love, and gladly give of ourselves, remembering that love is measured by sacrifice.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple28">The Third Note - Joy\nTertiaries, rejoicing in the Lord always, show in our lives the grace and beauty of divine joy. We remember that we follow the Son of Man, who came eating and drinking, who loved the birds and the flowers, who blessed little children, who was a friend to tax collectors and sinners, and who sat at the tables of both the rich and the poor. We delight in fun and laughter, rejoicing in God\'s world, its beauty and its living creatures, calling nothing common or unclean. We mix freely with all people, ready to bind up the broken-hearted and to bring joy into the lives of others. We carry within us an inner peace and happiness which others may perceive, even if they do not know its source.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple29">The Third Note, cont\'d\nThis joy is a divine gift, coming from union with God in Christ. It is still there even in times of darkness and difficulty, giving cheerful courage in the face of disappointment, and an inward serenity and confidence through sickness and suffering. Those who possess it can rejoice in weakness, insults, hardship, and persecutions for Christ\'s sake; for when we are weak, then we are strong.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFPrinciple30">The Three Notes\nThe humility, love and joy which mark the lives of Tertiaries are all God given graces. They can never be obtained by human effort. They are gifts of the Holy Spirit. The purpose of Christ is to work miracles through people who are willing to be emptied of self and to surrender to him. We then become channels of grace through whom his mighty work is done.\n</string>
    <string name="TSSFSunday">Sunday</string>
    <string name="TSSFMonday">Monday</string>
    <string name="TSSFTuesday">Tuesday</string>
    <string name="TSSFWednesday">Wednesday</string>
    <string name="TSSFThursday">Thursday</string>
    <string name="TSSFFriday">Friday</string>
    <string name="TSSFSaturday">Saturday</string>
</resources>